<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[quickoverview]]></title><description><![CDATA[A simple tech blog.]]></description><link>https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 06:42:24 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[The 5 Love Languages]]></title><description><![CDATA[People speak different love languages.We must be willing to learn our spouse’s primary love language if we are to be effective communicators…]]></description><link>https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview/the-five-love-languages/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview/the-five-love-languages/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;People speak different love languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must be willing to learn our spouse’s primary love language if we are to be effective communicators of love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something in our nature cries out to be loved by another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After studying scores of couples, she concluded that the average life span of a romantic obsession is two years. If it is a secretive love affair, it may last a little longer. Eventually, however, we all descend from the clouds and plant our feet on earth again. Our eyes are opened, and we see the warts of the other person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We fail to reckon with the reality of human nature. By nature, we are egocentric. Our world revolves around us. None of us is totally altruistic. The euphoria of the in-love experience only gives us that illusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can recognize the in-love experience for what it was—a temporary emotional high—and now pursue “real love” with our spouse. That kind of love is emotional in nature but not obsessional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;true love cannot begin until the in-love experience has run its course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if, once we return to the real world of human choice, we choose to be kind and generous, that is real love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If love is a choice, then they have the capacity to love after the “in-love” obsession has died and they have returned to the real world. That kind of love begins with an attitude—a way of thinking. Love is the attitude that says, “I am married to you, and I choose to look out for your interests.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Twain once said, “I can live for two months on a good compliment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, don’t ever mention painting the bedroom again.” I repeated, “Don’t ever mention it again.” “I don’t see how that’s going to help,” she said. “Look, you just told me that he knows that you want the bedroom painted. You don’t have to tell him anymore. He already knows. The second suggestion I have is that the next time your husband does anything good, give him a verbal compliment. If he takes the garbage out, say, ‘Dan, I want you to know that I really appreciate your taking the garbage out.’ Don’t say, ‘About time you took the garbage out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving verbal compliments is only one way to express words of affirmation to your spouse. Another dialect is encouraging words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“She didn’t want advice; she just wanted to know that I understood.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We forget that marriage is a relationship, not a project to be completed or a problem to solve. A relationship calls for sympathetic listening with a view to understanding the other person’s thoughts, feelings, and desires. We must be willing to give advice but only when it is requested and never in a condescending manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are influenced by our personality but not controlled by it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People tend to criticize their spouse most loudly in the area where they themselves have the deepest emotional need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the female, sexual desire is far more influenced by her emotions. If she feels loved and admired and appreciated by her husband, then she has a desire to be physically intimate with him. But without the emotional closeness she may have little physical desire. Her biological sexual drive is closely tied to her emotional need for love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to discover your primary love language is to examine what you do or say to express love to your spouse. Chances are what you are doing for her is what you wish she would do for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the difference between the in-love experience and the emotional need to feel loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The in-love experience temporarily meets one’s emotional need for love. It gives us the feeling that someone cares, that someone admires us and appreciates us. It is short-lived (usually two years or less)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost never do two people fall in love on the same day, and almost never do they fall out of love on the same day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is something you do for someone else, not something you do for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is not our only emotional need. Psychologists have observed that among our basic needs are the need for security, self-worth, and significance. Love, however, interfaces with all of those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, observe how you most often express love to others. If you are regularly doing acts of service for others, this may be your love language. If you are consistently, verbally affirming people, then Words of Affirmation is likely your love language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be true that more men have Physical Touch and Words of Affirmation as their love language and more women have Quality Time and Gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is a choice. We can request love, but we cannot demand love.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tiny Beautiful Things - Cheryl Strayed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tiny Beautiful Things - Cheryl StrayedBecause we are all, in the private kingdom of our hearts, desperate for the company of a wise, true…]]></description><link>https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview/Tiny-Beautiful-Things/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview/Tiny-Beautiful-Things/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Tiny Beautiful Things - Cheryl Strayed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we are all, in the private kingdom of our hearts, desperate for the company of a wise, true friend. Someone who isn’t embarrassed by our emotions, or her own, who recognizes that life is short and that all we have to offer, in the end, is love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was done writing it, I understood that things happened just as they were meant to. That I couldn’t have written my book before I did. I simply wasn’t capable of doing so, either as a writer or a person. To get to the point I had to get to to write my first book, I had to do everything I did in my twenties. I had to write a lot of sentences that never turned into anything and stories that never miraculously formed a novel. I had to read voraciously and compose exhaustive entries in my journals. I had to waste time and grieve my mother and come to terms with my childhood and have stupid and sweet and scandalous sexual relationships and grow up. In short, I had to gain the self-knowledge that Flannery O’Connor mentions in that quote I wrote on my chalkboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was only then, when I humbly surrendered, that I was able to do the work I needed to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you’ll think hard about that, honey bun. If you had a two-sided chalkboard in your living room I’d write humility on one side and surrender on the other for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You loathe yourself, sthe and yet you’re consumed by the grandiose ideas you have about your own importance. You’re up too high and down too low. Neither is the place where we get any work done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get the work done on the ground level. And the kindest thing I can do for you is to tell you to get your ass on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to get a job that makes others feel comfortable about what they perceive as your success. You don’t have to explain what you plan to do with your life. You don’t have to justify your education by demonstrating its financial rewards. You don’t have to maintain an impeccable credit score. Anyone who expects you to do any of those things has no sense of history or economics or science or the arts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you set new boundaries there is often strife and sorrow, but your life will be changed for the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are all savages inside. We all want to be the chosen, the beloved, the esteemed. There isn’t a person reading this who hasn’t at one point or another had that why not me? voice pop into the interior mix when something good has happened to someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the greatest truth isn’t in the confession, but rather in the lesson learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You go on by doing the best you can. You go on by being generous. You go on by being true. You go on by offering comfort to others who can’t go on. You go on by allowing the unbearable days to pass and allowing the pleasure in other days. You go on by finding a channel for your love and another for your rage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kindest and most meaningful thing anyone ever says to me is: Your mother would be proud of you. Finding a way in my grief to become the woman who my mother raised me to be is the most important way I have honored my mother. It has been the greatest salve to my sorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything about that boy pacing the hallway tells me a story I need to know: that we do not have the right to feel helpless, Helpless Mom. That we must help ourselves. That after destiny has delivered what it delivers, we are responsible for our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;understand that what you resolve will need to be resolved again. And again. You will come to know things that can only be known with the wisdom of age and the grace of years. Most of those things will have to do with forgiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will regret the small thing you didn’t say for the rest of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Models - Mark Manson]]></title><description><![CDATA[Models - Mark MansonEmerson once wrote, “What you do speaks so loudly I cannot hear what you say.”Your movement or lack of movement reflects…]]></description><link>https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview/models/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview/models/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Models - Mark Manson&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emerson once wrote, “What you do speaks so loudly I cannot hear what you say.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your movement or lack of movement reflects and alters emotions, not the words. Words are the side-effect. Sex is the side-effect. The game is emotions, emotions through movement. If you learn anything from this book, let that be it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a man, you don’t have to actually be rich and famous, you just have to show a lot of potential for being rich and famous to be considered extremely attractive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I put forth that women judge social status by behavior. Social status is determined by how you behave around other people, how other people behave around you, and how you treat yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the three tenants of being a high status and a highly attractive man: treat others well, be treated well by others, and treat yourself well. Later, we’ll see that these make up the Three Fundamentals that much of this book is based on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What they want is to be desired. They want to be desired to the point that a man loses complete self-control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has slowly been discovered over the past five years or so within the pick up industry, that the more physical assertiveness you pursue a woman with, the more aroused she becomes — sometimes even if she wasn’t interested in you to begin with. Your bold and aggressive pursuit of her often turns her on to the point where she comes around and wants to get to know you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How attractive a man is is inversely proportional to how needy he is. The more needy in his life, the less attractive and vice-versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I mean by neediness: being more invested in other people’s perceptions of you than your perception of yourself. Neediness plays out by people chronically investing themselves and their identities to receive validation from others around them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women are generally only attracted to men who are less invested in them, than they are in themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By less I mean that as a man, you should only be willing to sacrifice your thoughts/ feelings/motivations for a woman less than she is willing to do the same for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to lower one’s neediness by investing in himself rather than the woman he’s with. It’s the only long-term solution available to keep long-term relationships stable and happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rich man doesn’t need to tell people he’s rich. A confident man doesn’t need to tell people he’s confident. And a guy who “doesn’t give a fuck” doesn’t need to go around telling people he “doesn’t give a fuck.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confident people don’t date unconfident people and vice-versa. Women who aren’t needy don’t date men who are needy. They simply don’t have the patience nor the respect for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vulnerability makes perfect sense as an indicator to women of a male’s status and fitness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My belief is that women have been naturally selected to choose high status men based on their behavior first, and then their looks and accomplishments second — as looks and accomplishments tend be reflected by high status behavior, not the other way around. This high status behavior is a man who is comfortable with his vulnerability, who isn’t afraid to express who he is, warts and all, to the world. This plays out in multiple arenas — in the life decisions he makes (Part III), the extent of his courage (Part IV) and the way he communicates to others (Part V).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Psychologist Robert Glover says: “Humans are attracted to each other’s rough edges.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s OK to say something stupid. Women will not dislike you for your rejections and mistakes or saying something stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’ll like you for your ability to be OK with being rejected, to make mistakes, and to say something stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;man who becomes comfortable with his vulnerability becomes the opposite of needy. If neediness is prioritizing others’ perceptions about you over your own, then vulnerability is the exact opposite. Being vulnerable forces you to accept and prioritize your own perception over those of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you make yourself vulnerable, you will experience rejection. And as you experience rejection, you will be forced to upgrade your own sense of self worth. There’s no other option. Slowly, but surely you’ll chisel a “Don’t Give a Fuck” attitude out of yourself that is genuine yet giving at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two aspects of female attraction. Women are attracted to men who are of higher status than themselves (or in our terms, less needy). They are also aroused by men who desire them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women are tuned into a man’s overall behavior and demeanor — not what he says, not how much is in his bank account — but they look at what his behavior is and what it says about his level of neediness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women want a strong, independent, high status male — a “doesn’t take shit from anybody” bad boy — but they want this bad boy to have a depth and a sensitivity that they only open up and show when they’re around her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How attractive you are is based your non-needy behavior. Your nonneedy behavior is based on how vulnerable you’re able to make yourself. And how vulnerable you’re able to make yourself is based on how honest you are to yourself and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The only thing that’s Capital-T True is that you get to decide how you see things.”- David Foster Wallace,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can say the lamest and grossest (or funniest, depending on your perspective) thing to women, and if the sub-communication is, “I really don’t care if you laugh or run away horrified, but here’s who I am, take it or leave it,” this sub-communicates a rock-bottom low level of neediness, and an incredibly high level of vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a compliment comes from a man seeking nothing in return, it’s a gift of truth, a piece of his vulnerability and infinitely more powerful as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A woman’s desire is to be desired. But it has to be genuine desire. It can’t be a “I’ll desire you as long as you boost my ego and impress my friends” kind of desire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Man who feels like he needs to buy or steal a woman’s attention or affection through entertainment, money or superficiality is a man who is not confident in his identity and who is not genuinely attractive.A woman’s desire is to be desired. But it has to be genuine desire. It can’t be a “I’ll desire you as long as you boost my ego and impress my friends” kind of desire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not about what’s being said, it’s about the intention and sub-communication behind it. When you’re willing to cut a woman off and tell her when she’s out of line, when you’re willing to tell a woman what you will and will not tolerate in your life, this subcommunicates the most powerful elements of attraction to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you make it clear from the beginning that you are unwilling to put up with games, then not only will the women you attract stop playing games, but you’ll stop attracting women who do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My honesty and complete willingness to be rejected (or to reject them) demonstrates my nonneediness and for the first time, makes them incredibly attracted to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men who are not needy establish strict boundaries because they value their own time and happiness more than receiving the attention from a woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Any individual who wants to be a leader has to be controversial. Otherwise they don’t stand for anything.”- Richard M. Nixon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You CANNOT be an attractive and lifechanging presence to some women without being a joke or an embarrassment to others. You simply can’t. You have to be controversial. You have to polarize. It’s the name of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’d be surprised how many women will respond with attraction to nothing other than a man who is bold and willing to make a move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember women are turned on by men who desire them. They are also turned on by the behavior of high status. When you’re expressing your truth and showing shameless desire for her, you are demonstrating both of these qualities that turns her on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I have failed over and over and over again in my life. And that is why I succeed.”- Michael Jordan, Athlete&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Show me someone who is successful at anything and I’ll show you someone who has been rejected and failed more than you can ever know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with any failure, it’s not until you’ve been rejected a certain amount that you realize how insignificant it actually is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What stops the vast majority of men out there from going out and getting what they want (and deserve) in their love lives, is that they take rejection, failure and incompatibilities personally, as if it says something true about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only truth about you is what you decide about yourself. And the more truth you know about yourself, the more you’ll be unaffected by others’ reactions to you and the more attractive you’ll become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Three Fundamentals are: Creating an attractive and appealing lifestyle; Overcoming your fears and anxiety around women, and mastering the expression of your emotions and communicating fluidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Man sacrifices his health in order to make money. Then he sacrifices his money to recuperate his health. And then he is so anxious about the future that he does not enjoy the present; the result being that he does not live in the present or the future; he lives as if he is never going to die, and then dies having never really lived.”- The Dalai Lama&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Man sacrifices his health in order to make money. Then he sacrifices his money to recuperate his health. And then he is so anxious about the future that he does not enjoy the present; the result being that he does not live in the present or the future; he lives as if he is never going to die, and then dies having never really lived.”- The Dalai Lama&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;women judge men far less based on actual physical dimensions and far more on style, grooming and how they present themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the less well off SHE is, the more important money will be to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s simple: money, looks and success are all indicators of status. Women are attracted to status. Behavior is also an indicator of status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of social proof comes from influence psychology and is the idea that as humans, when we see many other people valuing something, we will unconsciously value it ourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also why the best way to net a Top 1% girl is to connect with her genuinely and emotionally as soon as possible. Find something that you like about her other than her looks and relate that to her honestly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or as the old saying goes: “Tell the beautiful girls they’re smart and tell the smart girls that they’re beautiful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;your life and everything that it encompasses, is a reflection of your emotional investment in yourself. And the more invested you are in yourself, the less needy you are with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;your outward appearance is a reflection of your selfinvestment (or lack thereof).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;women judge men’s physical attractiveness based on their clothes, grooming and body language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guys are spending hours and hours at the gym obsessing over their biceps and bench presses, when the sexiest muscles in their body have always been in their throat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You want to focus more on the literature. Here are some names to start with: Gabriel Garcia Marquez, Ernest Hemingway, Virginia Woolf, James Joyce, Vladmir Nabokov, John Steinbeck, Charles seckDickens, Leo Tolstoy, F. Scott Fitzgerald, William Faulkner, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ayn Rand’s “Atlas Shrugged” changed my life in college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;my high school literature teacher always told us: “You read literature because you can NEVER meet enough people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poor lifestyle choices reflect a lack of investment in yourself, which in turn causes you to be more needy around others for validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poor lifestyle choices reflect a lack of investment in yourself, which in turn causes you to be more needy around others for validation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Life shrinks and expands in proportion to one’s courage.”- Anais Nin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women communicate more in feelings and specifically, through intentions. Sure, they still pay attention to the facts and stories going on on the surface, but what’s actually communicated to them is the intention and feeling underneath.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is sub-communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You know, if you weren’t so cute, I’d ditch you for saying that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is more or less the blueprint of seduction: a strong, high status, attractive exterior (lifestyle and looks), fearless, and able to open up and share your vulnerable side with her (and theoretically, only her). Women get weak in the knees for this. And it’s not even conscious in them most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions Versus Statements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I love olives in my drink. When I was a kid I used to eat them straight out of the jar,” is far more interesting than, “Do you like olives in your drink?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cold-reading is a skill where you’re able to intuitively “know” something about someone else without actually knowing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s like being a psychic without&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What do you do for work?” translates to: “You seem to be a creative person. I bet your job is interesting.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“How do you guys know each other?” translates to: “You guys look like you’ve been friends for a long time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing people love more than talking about themselves is hearing about themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our level of intimacy with one another doesn’t come from how much we talk about, as much as it comes from the experiences we share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every decision should be yours and she should be expected to follow it. Remove, “What do you want to do now?” from your dating vocabulary. Never say it again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proximity: This one is subtle, but the more you work on your lifestyle, body language and style, the more of these you will get. It’s when a woman places herself near you when she doesn’t have to.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>