<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[quickoverview]]></title><description><![CDATA[A simple tech blog.]]></description><link>https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 09:06:08 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[MindSet]]></title><description><![CDATA[kjdakjdsal
asjbcdskc
askjcbdsackkjsac
ascjbsakcbjac
asckajbvclancaskjbcxlkjsabvca
ascb,sabc,aasckjbsakcjbsalcnsa
ascbaksjbca
ascabs vclkjaca…]]></description><link>https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview/mindset/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview/mindset/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;kjdakjdsal
asjbcdskc
askjcbdsackkjsac
ascjbsakcbjac
asckajbvclanc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;askjbcxlkjsabvca
ascb,sabc,a&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;asckjbsakcjbsalcnsa
ascbaksjbca
ascabs vclkjac&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a ckdsabvcsajbcakjcba&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The 5 Love Languages]]></title><description><![CDATA[People speak different love languages.We must be willing to learn our spouse’s primary love language if we are to be effective communicators…]]></description><link>https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview/the-five-love-languages/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview/the-five-love-languages/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;People speak different love languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must be willing to learn our spouse’s primary love language if we are to be effective communicators of love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something in our nature cries out to be loved by another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After studying scores of couples, she concluded that the average life span of a romantic obsession is two years. If it is a secretive love affair, it may last a little longer. Eventually, however, we all descend from the clouds and plant our feet on earth again. Our eyes are opened, and we see the warts of the other person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We fail to reckon with the reality of human nature. By nature, we are egocentric. Our world revolves around us. None of us is totally altruistic. The euphoria of the in-love experience only gives us that illusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can recognize the in-love experience for what it was—a temporary emotional high—and now pursue “real love” with our spouse. That kind of love is emotional in nature but not obsessional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;true love cannot begin until the in-love experience has run its course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if, once we return to the real world of human choice, we choose to be kind and generous, that is real love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If love is a choice, then they have the capacity to love after the “in-love” obsession has died and they have returned to the real world. That kind of love begins with an attitude—a way of thinking. Love is the attitude that says, “I am married to you, and I choose to look out for your interests.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Twain once said, “I can live for two months on a good compliment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One, don’t ever mention painting the bedroom again.” I repeated, “Don’t ever mention it again.” “I don’t see how that’s going to help,” she said. “Look, you just told me that he knows that you want the bedroom painted. You don’t have to tell him anymore. He already knows. The second suggestion I have is that the next time your husband does anything good, give him a verbal compliment. If he takes the garbage out, say, ‘Dan, I want you to know that I really appreciate your taking the garbage out.’ Don’t say, ‘About time you took the garbage out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Giving verbal compliments is only one way to express words of affirmation to your spouse. Another dialect is encouraging words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“She didn’t want advice; she just wanted to know that I understood.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We forget that marriage is a relationship, not a project to be completed or a problem to solve. A relationship calls for sympathetic listening with a view to understanding the other person’s thoughts, feelings, and desires. We must be willing to give advice but only when it is requested and never in a condescending manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are influenced by our personality but not controlled by it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People tend to criticize their spouse most loudly in the area where they themselves have the deepest emotional need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the female, sexual desire is far more influenced by her emotions. If she feels loved and admired and appreciated by her husband, then she has a desire to be physically intimate with him. But without the emotional closeness she may have little physical desire. Her biological sexual drive is closely tied to her emotional need for love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to discover your primary love language is to examine what you do or say to express love to your spouse. Chances are what you are doing for her is what you wish she would do for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the difference between the in-love experience and the emotional need to feel loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The in-love experience temporarily meets one’s emotional need for love. It gives us the feeling that someone cares, that someone admires us and appreciates us. It is short-lived (usually two years or less)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost never do two people fall in love on the same day, and almost never do they fall out of love on the same day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is something you do for someone else, not something you do for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is not our only emotional need. Psychologists have observed that among our basic needs are the need for security, self-worth, and significance. Love, however, interfaces with all of those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, observe how you most often express love to others. If you are regularly doing acts of service for others, this may be your love language. If you are consistently, verbally affirming people, then Words of Affirmation is likely your love language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be true that more men have Physical Touch and Words of Affirmation as their love language and more women have Quality Time and Gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love is a choice. We can request love, but we cannot demand love.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Tiny Beautiful Things - Cheryl Strayed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tiny Beautiful Things - Cheryl StrayedBecause we are all, in the private kingdom of our hearts, desperate for the company of a wise, true…]]></description><link>https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview/Tiny-Beautiful-Things/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://awaisazmat.github.io/quickoverview/Tiny-Beautiful-Things/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Tiny Beautiful Things - Cheryl Strayed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we are all, in the private kingdom of our hearts, desperate for the company of a wise, true friend. Someone who isn’t embarrassed by our emotions, or her own, who recognizes that life is short and that all we have to offer, in the end, is love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was done writing it, I understood that things happened just as they were meant to. That I couldn’t have written my book before I did. I simply wasn’t capable of doing so, either as a writer or a person. To get to the point I had to get to to write my first book, I had to do everything I did in my twenties. I had to write a lot of sentences that never turned into anything and stories that never miraculously formed a novel. I had to read voraciously and compose exhaustive entries in my journals. I had to waste time and grieve my mother and come to terms with my childhood and have stupid and sweet and scandalous sexual relationships and grow up. In short, I had to gain the self-knowledge that Flannery O’Connor mentions in that quote I wrote on my chalkboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was only then, when I humbly surrendered, that I was able to do the work I needed to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope you’ll think hard about that, honey bun. If you had a two-sided chalkboard in your living room I’d write humility on one side and surrender on the other for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You loathe yourself, sthe and yet you’re consumed by the grandiose ideas you have about your own importance. You’re up too high and down too low. Neither is the place where we get any work done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get the work done on the ground level. And the kindest thing I can do for you is to tell you to get your ass on the floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to get a job that makes others feel comfortable about what they perceive as your success. You don’t have to explain what you plan to do with your life. You don’t have to justify your education by demonstrating its financial rewards. You don’t have to maintain an impeccable credit score. Anyone who expects you to do any of those things has no sense of history or economics or science or the arts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you set new boundaries there is often strife and sorrow, but your life will be changed for the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are all savages inside. We all want to be the chosen, the beloved, the esteemed. There isn’t a person reading this who hasn’t at one point or another had that why not me? voice pop into the interior mix when something good has happened to someone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the greatest truth isn’t in the confession, but rather in the lesson learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You go on by doing the best you can. You go on by being generous. You go on by being true. You go on by offering comfort to others who can’t go on. You go on by allowing the unbearable days to pass and allowing the pleasure in other days. You go on by finding a channel for your love and another for your rage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kindest and most meaningful thing anyone ever says to me is: Your mother would be proud of you. Finding a way in my grief to become the woman who my mother raised me to be is the most important way I have honored my mother. It has been the greatest salve to my sorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything about that boy pacing the hallway tells me a story I need to know: that we do not have the right to feel helpless, Helpless Mom. That we must help ourselves. That after destiny has delivered what it delivers, we are responsible for our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;understand that what you resolve will need to be resolved again. And again. You will come to know things that can only be known with the wisdom of age and the grace of years. Most of those things will have to do with forgiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will regret the small thing you didn’t say for the rest of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>